The Drop is a drama, crime film directed by Michaël R. Roskam.
Bob Saginowski finds himself at the center of a robbery gone awry and entwined in an investigation that digs deep into the
neighborhood's past where friends, families, and foes all work together to make a living - no matter the cost.
Bob, played by Tom Hardy.
Nadia, played by Noomi Rapace.
Cousin Marv, played by James Gandolfini.
Eric Deeds, played by Matthias Schoenaerts.
Detective Torres, played by John Ortiz.
Dottie, played by Ann Dowd.
The Drop is a 2014 American crime film directed by Michaël R.
Roskam and written by Dennis Lehane, based on his
2009 short story "Animal Rescue".
It follows Bob Saginowski, a barman who becomes entangled in an
investigation after the mafia-run bar where he works is robbed.
It stars Tom Hardy, Noomi Rapace, James Gandolfini (in his
final film role), and Matthias Schoenaerts.
It premiered at the 2014 Toronto International Film Festival and was released
theatrically on September 12, 2014, by Fox Searchlight Pictures.
It received generally positive reviews and grossed $4.1 million during its opening
weekend and $18.9 million worldwide, against a budget of $12.6 million.
The film explores themes of robbery, hitman, winter, blackmail, crime boss.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.